

I'm a software engineer currently working in web and mobile development. As an engineer, I strive to maintain equity, safety, and forward thinking within my teams and most importantly, myself. I use multidisciplinary experiences to create a team environment where its engineers can grow.

Skills

Swift (SwiftUI, UIKit, Combine, XCTest), C# (Xamarin, .NET, Xamarin Forms) Mobile Development

Web Development TypeScript/JavaScript (React, Redux, Node), CSS (SCSS, Styled-Components) HTML, JSX

Other Software Java, Python, C++, AWS, (EC2, S3, CloudFormation, CodeBuild, CodePipeline)

Experience

DraftKings Remote, Boston, MA

MOBILE APP ENGINEER Aug 2022 - Present

• Skills Utilized: C#, Xamarin, Swift, SwiftUI, .NET, iOS and Android Development

- Released the Player Page, Player Stats and News, and College Navigation features to the Xamarin Android and iOS DraftKings app
- Refactored the Event and League pages to ensure peak performance during the Super Bowl and March Madness events
- · Increased app stability through higher quality code review, unit testing, functional testing, and integration testing

Posterity Remote, New York, NY

FRONT-END SOFTWARE ENGINEER Feb 2022 - Jun 2022

- Skills Utilized: React, TypeScript, NextJS, Styled Components, CSS, Storybook, Entrepreneurship
- Implemented and tested the Posterity.life progressive web application using TypeScript and React
- Integrated Storybook to increase design accuracy of UI components and isolate UI testing
- · Created reusable components and layouts based on Figma designs to reduce codebase complexity and build time
- · Regression tested all new components and pages to ensure seamless integration with both the new PWA and legacy application

PayPal Remote, Boston, MA

IOS Engineer Co-Op / Brand Architecture Intern

Jun 2021 - Dec 2021

• Skills Utilized: Swift, UIKit, Postman, XCode, Unit Testing, Market Research, Business Strategy, Competitive Analysis Implemented new localization-specific features and UI elements for the EU release of the PayPal Business Debit Card

- Conducted unit tests, regression tests, and integration tests to ensure that all new features work consistently throughout all languages and versions
- Refactored and modernized outdated client-side Swift code for iOS PayPal Card products
- Researched new markets, mapped competition, and developed product names for potential new product offerings with PayPal's Brand Architecture team
- Volunteered with The Network for Teaching Entrepreneurship to teach 6–12th grade students entrepreneurial skills and judge business ideas

Wayfair Boston, MA

• Skills Utilized: Swift, UIKit, Autolayout, GraphQL, UI Design, Mobile Development

- · Developed the "Product Details" page, "Related Product" carousels, and product image carousels for the Wayfair 2020 iOS redesign
- Architected and implemented pages on the Wayfair iOS App using Swift and GraphQL on Wayfair's Product Detail Page and Shopping Cart teams
- · Created "Related Items" page, "Frequently Bought Together" carousel, "Additional Information" menus, and image carousels on all product pages
- Collaborated with software and QA engineers to implement multitasking split-view on iPad throughout the Wayfair iOS App.
- · Volunteered to host charity events on behalf of Wayfair to raise funds for St. Jude's Children's Hospital

Broadridge Financial Solutions

Deer Park, NY Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

• Skills Utilized: DevOps, AWS (CloudFormation, S3, IAM, EC2), Javascript, UI Design, Groovy, Jenkins, Marketing, Public Speaking

- · Constructed the foundations of an automated, cloud-based DevOps architecture to decrease the spin-up time of Broadridge Digital B2B products
- Optimized AWS microservice suite to reduce costs by 90% compared to the current on-premise solution
- Designed a Broadridge online digital investor resource mobile app, which would massively reduce printing and mailing costs

Projects

DEVOPS INTERN

IOS ENGINEER CO-OP

Carrot Wolf Hershnagpal.com **Egyptian Rat-Screw WayMovies** Web Checkers

A Rogue-like game written in functional JavaScript using Redux for state management and Storybook for UI Testing My personal website written in functional TypeScript with Styled Components and Storybook, using AWS CI/CD pipelines

An iOS version of my favorite card game, without the hand-slapping, written in Swift using SwiftUI and Combine An iOS app that allows browsing, searching, and saving movies, powered by TMDB. Written in Swift using UIKit and Autolayout

An online checkers site where you can play against your friends or an Al player. Made using Java, Freemarker, and Spark

An RIT Sponsored startup for whom I created the MVP web application in React and Node, with MongoDB and Twilio integration

Education

FiTR SKills

Rochester Institute of Technology

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, MINORS IN COMMUNICATION AND PSYCHOLOGY

2023 HERSH NAGPAL RESUME